<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Insights on Carbon Slash</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/insights/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Insights on Carbon Slash</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/insights/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Kenya&#39;s Load Shedding Crisis Reveals Renewable Energy Investment Opportunity.</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/insights/kenya-load-shedding-renewable-opportunity/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/insights/kenya-load-shedding-renewable-opportunity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-load-shedding-crisis-a-grid-under-stress&#34;&gt;The Load Shedding Crisis: A Grid Under Stress&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Kenya boasts one of the world&amp;rsquo;s greenest national grids, with over &lt;strong&gt;90% of electricity&lt;/strong&gt; generated from renewable sources like geothermal, hydro, and wind. Yet, recurring load shedding and system failures reveal two key problems:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Centralized Vulnerability:&lt;/strong&gt; The grid relies on high-voltage transmission lines to move power from geothermal plants (like Olkaria) and hydro dams over long distances to major cities. A single fault—whether weather-related, technical, or even due to vandalism—can cascade into a nationwide blackout.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Climate Exposure:&lt;/strong&gt; Periods of drought severely impact Kenya’s crucial &lt;strong&gt;hydroelectric dams&lt;/strong&gt;, forcing the system to compensate with costly, dirty, and unreliable thermal power or, worse, implementing planned outages to protect the grid.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;These vulnerabilities translate directly into lost revenue, compromised security, and a drag on Kenya&amp;rsquo;s ambitious economic goals.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Carbon Capture: Policy and Market Dynamics.</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/insights/understanding-carbon-capture-markets/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 14:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/insights/understanding-carbon-capture-markets/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-100-per-tonne-challenge&#34;&gt;The $100 Per Tonne Challenge&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For carbon capture and storage (CCS) to be economically viable at scale, the industry must meet the challenge of lowering the cost of capture, transport, and sequestration. Government incentives, particularly those focused on long-term storage, are key to scaling up this critical climate solution.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
